

# Firdaus Samad

## Front End Developer

## CONTACT

- **(** +6012-9565630
- mfirdausabdsamad@gmail.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/muham mad-firdaus-abd-samad-02946665/
- Apartment Lestari, Damansara
  Damai

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor Degree of Science Computer Software Development Universiti Sultan Zainal Abidin

2011 - 2015

Diploma of Electronic Computer Engineering

Politeknik Sultan Azlan Shah

2008 - 2011

# **CERTIFICATE**

- CERTIPORT INTERNET AND COMPUTING
- PROFICIENCY IN ENTERPRISE COMMUNICATION
- CERTIFICATE OF INTERNET PROTOCOL ASSOCIATION(CIPA)
- INFOSYS FOUNDATION (JAVA, RDBMS, C
- LANGUAGE AND OPERATING SYSTEM)
- MAGNOLIA FOR FRONT-END DEVELOPER

#### **SKILLS**

- Scripting: HTML5,jQuery, JavaScript, Css,Bootstrap, AngularJS
- Technology: Liferay 6.x, 7.x CE/DXP,Liferay 6.2 EE, Git, MagnoliaCMS, Wordpress

### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

As a Senior Front End Developer, I am responsible for developing Liferay themes and HTML templates, as well as helping team member on work related to html, css and javascript.

In my role, I have worked on several high-profile projects, including Central Bank Malaysia, SGInnovate, Canon Singapore, the Energy Market Company (EMC) in Singapore, and several others.

Some of these projects are developed using Liferay, while others are developed using AngularJS.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Senior Front End Developer

#### **Cxrus Solutions**

2019 - Present

- Responsible for designing, building, and maintaining the user-facing components of a website or application. This includes designing and implementing the user interface, writing and testing code for the website or application, and ensuring that the website or application is visually appealing, responsive, and easy to use. Working on Liferay6.2, 7.xx.
- Past Project:
- o Central Bank Malaysia main corporate website and other component(Anti Money Laundering microsite and Islamic Finance microsite), developed using Liferay DXP
- o Canon Singapore, developed using AngularJS
- o Lee Kuan Yew School of Public Policy Alumni Portal, developed using HTML/CSS/JS
- o SGInnovate developed, using AngularJS
- o Certis Singapore, developed using AngularJS
- o Allianz Cancer Singapore Portal, developed using AngularJS
- o Allianz Insurance Singapore Portal, developed using AngularJS
- o Cxrus Solution website developed and maintain, using Magnolia CMS

#### Web Developer Skali Group

- Developed Liferay front-end including theming
- SKALI Corporate Website using Liferay 6.2 EE

  Ping in Market and (FFN) to add a significant and a
- RinggitWise by Financial Network (FENetwork), developed using Liferay 7.0
- Board of Engineering Malaysia, developed using Liferay 6.2
- Bursa Malaysia's BusinessContinuity Management portal, developed using Liferay 7.1

#### Front End Developer

#### **Digital Pinnacle Sdn Bhd**

2015 - 2016

2017 - 2019

• Responsible for designing and implementing the user interface of a website or application. This includes writing code to create and style web pages and developing scripts and other functionality to make the user experience more interactive and engaging.

Skali Group

- •Here is the list of project I developed
- Etiqa.com.my
- Superkids.my
- Aibay
- Vehicle Tracking System

#### Web Developer/System Analyst

2015-2016

- Developer Skali.net portal using Liferay6.2 EE
- Developed SUK Pahang using Liferay6.0 CE
- Developed Perbadanan Labuan portal using Liferay 6.2 EE
- Developed Royal SelangorGolf Club using Liferay 6.2 CE